[ Thunder Crashing ]
[ Waves Lapping ]
[ Bell Tolling ]
[ Man Humming ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Birds Twittering ]
[ Action Figure ] Action Man patrol , open fire !
This is your commandant speaking .
Mortar attack . Dig in .
[ Crow Cawing ]
What are you reading ?
I was just trying to find the answer to a question Christine was asking me :
" If the world 's round , why is a frozen pond flat ? "
[ Chuckles ]
That 's a good question .
Aha ! " Lake Ontario curves more than three degrees ...
from its easternmost shore to its westernmost shore . "
So frozen water isn 't flat .
- Nothing is what it seems . - My cigarette ‒
Did you put all the window slides together ?
No , I put the duplicates in my tray .
[ Action Figure ] Action Man patrol , fall in .
Enemy in sight . Range : 1,000 .
- [ Glass Clatters ] - Oh , shit ! Oh .
[ Woman ] What 's the matter ?
Nothing .
Dad ! Dad !
[ Inhales Sharply ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Wailing ]
[ Low , Prolonged Groan ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Gasping Sobs ]
[ Sobbing ]
- [ Sobbing ] - [ Screams ]
Tutto è marcio .
La pietra è come tabacco .
Scavo ancora ?
No , è tardi . Andiamo via .
Mia moglie mi aspetta al ristorante .
- Ci vediamo domani a San Nicolò . - Sì , domani , sì .
Grazie tante , eh ?
Ciao .
- Hi . - Hi .
- What are you doing ? - Just writing to Johnny .
- What did you say ? - Nothing . It 's just a letter . How did it go ?
Oh , God . The deeper we get , the more byzantine it gets .
- I 'm restoring a fake . - [ Bell Rings ]
- It 's incredible you can 't change your course . - They haven 't got the bread .
The options are restore the fake or let it sink into the sea .
What did you say ?
Well , I said , " Daddy 's still hard at work on the windows at St. Nicholas ...
our beautiful 16th-century church .
He 's done incredible stuff . I can 't tell the difference ...
between his repaired windows and the originals .
I 'm going to try to get slides of the two and send them to you .
Hope my friend Ellis is being more reasonable this term . "
That 's his group captain or something .
" I 'm enclosing the money for your gym shoes .
Buy ones with padded soles . The others hurt your feet .
Ask Matron for those especially . Might as well be kind to yourself . "
- Just another boring letter . - God , it 's cold .
[ Women Chattering , Indistinct ]
- [ Wind Gusting ] - Oh . Oh , dear .
- [ Horn Honking ] - I 've got something in my eye .
- Can I help ? - No , no , no .
It smarts . No , no , no .
Want me to put something on the end ?
No . Why don 't you send him a card yourself ?
It 's so cold in here , the waiters don 't come . Senta !
I must take some time off and ‒
Signori ?
Uh ‒ What do you want ?
Uh , I 'll have what I had last night .
Pollo soppresso ...
and a scampi ai ferri .
Vino bianco . Due insalate verdi ?
- Okay . - It 's okay ? Sì , va bene .
- Did you see the bishop this morning ? - No ‒
I 'm terribly sorry .
Sorry .
What ?
No , she 's got something in her eye , that 's all .
- [ Man Speaking Italian ] - [ Woman ] I don 't know what he 's talking about .
I think I 'd better go and help them .
Excuse me . Excuse me .
Perhaps I can show you where it is .
It 's a bit well-disguised .
Thank you so much . Very kind .
I hope you don 't think us rude .
- " Rude " ? Why ? - Staring at you out there .
We 're frightful starers , the two of us .
Comes from living in the country . Country people always stare more .
- I 'm frightfully sorry . - I didn 't notice , so don 't worry .
- You 've been very kind . Which eye is it ? - Here . The left one .
- Let me help . - How can you help ?
- I can try . - No . You nearly put Jocelyn 's eye out ...
the last time you tried poking about .
- [ Moans ] - Well , perhaps ‒
Perhaps I can help . Do you think ?
Oh , that 's awfully kind of you .
Oh , dear . [ Exclaiming ]
My sister is blind , you see .
- Oh , I see . - Yes .
[ Motor Rumbling ]
[ Windshield Wipers Clacking ]
[ Doors Close ]
[ Woman ] I see it . Ooh .
A little tiny black speck .
- I think I got it . - Well done .
Thank you very much . Goodness !
You do remind me of my daughter .
Oh , really ?
- Only her hair is darker . - Oh .
Well , here , take your handkerchief .
You 're sad .
You 're so sad , and there 's no need to be .
- My sister 's psychic . - She wants you to know ‒
I 've seen her ...
and she wants you to know that she 's happy .
I 've seen your little girl ...
sitting between you and your husband ...
and she was laughing .
Yes . Oh , yes .
She 's with you . She 's with you , my dear .
And she 's laughing !
I 'm sorry if we stared .
She 's wearing a ‒
a shiny little mac .
Christine !
Oh , but she 's laughing , she 's laughing .
She 's happy as can be .
Oh , you 're very like her .
The forehead and the eyes ‒
- Is that better ? - Yes .
- Shall I fetch your husband ? - No , no , don 't ‒
- I 'm all right . Thank you . - Good . Jolly good .
I think if you just leave me alone , I 'll be fine .
All right , my dear .
Did you ‒
Did you really see her ?
She was there .
[ Shuddering ]
I felt you were right .
I felt we should .
[ Cash Register Rings ]
[ Man ] Signore .
Ah . I sent your food back to get it warm .
- The mastic that works is number three . Senta ! - Oh , God .
- I 've got to stand up . - You okay ?
I 'm sorry .
Signore . Signore .
Grazie tante , eh ?
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Children Shouting , Laughing ]
[ Woman Laughing ]
[ Children Shouting , Chattering In Italian ]
There 's nothing but children out there .
It was the nearest hospital . How are you feeling ?
- Fine . I 've been playing with them . - I talked to the doctor ‒
- John , Christine is still with us . - Christine is dead , Laura .
- Christine is dead . - Of course , of course . I know .
But you know the two ladies in the restaurant ?
They were watching us eating . They kept staring .
They told me this , ' cause they could see ...
Christine sitting between us .
This is two people we don 't even know !
Listen , listen , now .
There 's one who 's blind . She 's the one that can see .
She 's the one that has the second sight . She 's blind .
She described to me Christine 's red plastic mac .
Laura ‒
- John , listen , I 'm perfectly all right . - Laura ‒
I haven 't felt as good in months and months .
I feel really fine . I don 't need pills .
I 'm not going crazy . I feel really great .
When did the doctor say you could leave ?
Oh , anytime . I only fainted .
John , I wish you 'd believe me . I really feel fine .
- I really feel good at last . I feel fine . - I believe you .
Seeing is believing . I believe you . [ Chuckling ]
Put your shoes on .
[ Shouting , Chattering ]
[ Horn Sounding ]
- Via , via ! - Fermo ! Fermo !
Dobbiamo passare di là . Devo passare .
Un omicidio ! Sta ' fermo !
Che è successo ?
C 'è stato un omicidio . Sta ' fermo .
- What did he say ? " Homicide " ? - Yeah .
- [ Italian ] - [ Horn Sounds ]
[ Italian Continues ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Horn Sounding ]
I thought this was the place ‒ Isn 't this where you were ‒
No .
[ Bell Tolling ]
I want to stop at this church .
[ John ] It 's closed .
Why that one ?
Just ‒ Just wanted to . I want to say a prayer .
Oh , Laura .
[ Pipe Organ ]
- I don 't like this church at all . - Well , I do .
[ Coins Rattling ]
- Do you have any change ? - Yeah .
I 'm going to light a candle for her .
- How much are candles ? - Fifty .
I don 't have any fifties .
Maybe I 'll light six .
Laura .
Thank you , my love .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Man ] The Madonna is by Antonio Rizzo in about 1490 .
The grille work is also by Rizzo .
Note the flowers woven into the motif . [ Continues , Indistinct ]
Ahh !
- [ Gasps ] Jesus ! - I doubt it , hypocrite !
The bishop ! I 'm an hour and a half late .
[ Italian ]
- [ Continues ] - [ Italian Continues ]
[ Ducks Quacking ]
- How are you , John ? - Sorry .
Please forgive us . It was entirely my fault . Nothing to do with John .
A woman to share your sins with .
Laura , you 're looking much better .
- I 'm really terribly sorry . - [ Scoffs ] Oh , please .
These workmen took me around the church .
You have made some great advances .
I 'd like you to look at the mosaics . They need to be refired .
I 've already been much too long .
Now , when are you both coming to stay with me ?
Thursday , if that 's all right . Is that all right ?
I 'll look forward to it .
I 've taken samples from the pilings . We 're in trouble down there too . If I can ‒
The churches belong to God ...
but he doesn 't seem to care about them .
Does he have other priorities ?
We have stopped listening .
Are you Christian , Laura ?
Ah ... I don 't know .
I 'm kind to animals and children .
[ Chuckles ] St. Nicholas of this church ...
is the patron saint of scholars and children .
An interesting combination , don 't you think ?
[ Laura ] Uh ‒
We must talk , John .
Thursday .
- I 'll have your room ready . - [ Laura ] Thank you .
I 'll have the mastic samples by then .
The acidity in the air is breaking down all the adhesive .
I look forward to hearing about it Thursday .
- Ciao . - Bye .
You have the sensation he doesn 't give an ecclesiastical fuck about the church ?
Why did he ask me if I was a Christian ?
Because you kissed his ring .
What in God 's name made you do that ?
- Ciao , Giorgio . - Ci vediamo domani .
Sì .
No , seriously .
You know ...
your bishop really makes me feel quite uneasy .
He probably makes God feel slightly less than immaculate .
- No , I don 't mean that . - Signori ! - Signore !
- La chiave ‒ - La chiave ce l 'ho io .
Good !
[ Italian ]
[ Radio Switching Stations ]
I 'm gonna get down to some work tomorrow .
Enough of this idling around .
[ John ] What ?
[ Radio Switching Stations ]
[ Classical ]
Are you absolutely sure we don 't have to book at this place tonight ?
I don 't want that same performance that happened last time .
- What place ? - Oh , John !
The place we 're going to be eating at .
Yeah , I 'm sure .
I didn 't bring any Neutrogena again .
[ John Chuckling ] Wow !
You 'll have to read this .
What are you doing ?
[ Bath Water Running ]
- I can 't hear what you 're saying . - I 'm shouting !
- I still can 't hear . - What are you doing ?
I 'm having a bath .
You heard me that time .
[ Humming ]
[ Shower Running ]
[ Shuts Off ]
Those lumps are coming back on the side of your waist .
See ?
I weigh 85 kilos , which is 190 pounds .
Are you okay ?
Yeah , I 'm okay .
[ Knock At Door ]
Uh , come in .
- [ Woman ] Posso rifare la stanza ? - Sì , sì .
Oh .
Scusi . Torno più tardi .
Isn 't it a miracle I didn 't hurt myself when I fainted today ?
No , the unconscious body reacts faster than the mind ever can .
- Perhaps . - Hmm ?
You 've got toothpaste all over your mouth .
Eat it off .
I can 't get it off .
[ Exhales Sharply ]
This .
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Laura ] That was a long time before we came back .
[ John ] No , it wasn 't .
- Yes , it was . - It wasn 't .
- Was it ? - Mm-hmm .
Signori , you will be eating here tonight , I hope .
No , thank you , signor Alexander . We 're going to eat out tonight .
Ah , peccato . Buona serata .
- Grazie a lei . - Buona sera .
[ Italian ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Waves Lapping ]
[ Clock Chimes ]
[ Laura ] Hey .
Come here . I think I 've found the way .
[ John ] No , we 've been over this bridge already .
[ Laura ] Uh ‒
Well , I never minded being lost in Venice .
[ Chuckling ]
We go down here , take the second left ...
and we end up right in front of San Zaccaria .
- Oh , yeah ? - Yeah ... I think .
Nice dark little alley .
[ Laura Chuckles , Coughs ]
- [ John ] Yes , this is it . - It isn 't .
- Yes , it is . - It isn 't , though .
- Come on . - [ Clattering , Echoing ]
No , it isn 't .
[ Water Trickling ]
[ Laura Gasps ] Oh ! Rats !
I 'm getting out of here .
I know this place .
This is it . It 's the Ponte Giretto .
What ?
- This is it . - No , it 's on ‒
[ Man Gasps ]
[ Man Screams ]
[ Shouting ]
What 's that , John ?
It 's okay . I found the real world . It 's down here . Come on .
[ Man Gasping ]
- What on earth was that ? - It was a cat or a rat or something .
- Maybe it was something I did . - How could it be a rat ?
[ People Chattering ]
What ? This ‒
This was just around the corner from where we were .
- I know where we are now . - [ Indistinct ]
[ Men Speaking Italian ]
Sta ' attento !
[ Men Grunting Rhythmically ]
[ Rhythmic Grunting Continues ]
[ John ] Più in alto .
Adagio .
[ John ] Sì . In alto .
Va bene . Sì .
- [ Man ] Pronti ? - Attenzione !
[ Continues , Indistinct ]
[ John Speaking Italian , Indistinct ]
[ Man ] Pronti ?
Hello ?
- Hello . - Hello .
How extraordinary to see you ! Oh , it 's Mrs. Baxter .
- Yes , yes , I know . - My husband 's restoring this church , you know .
Sì , sì , sì , sì , sì .
Ecco qua .
- Espere . - Un momento . Lo sfaccio .
Yes . Yes , I do . I remember her hair .
Light hair , and silky soft ...
and she ‒ she tossed it as she laughed .
- Did she die suddenly ? - Heather , you 've no right to !
No , I really wouldn 't mind talking about it , actually .
I 'll just get my coat . Would you mind waiting ?
I won 't be a second , all right ? Thank you .
[ Italian Continues ]
[ Laura ] Sunday afternoon .
We 'd just finished lunch .
Oh , I used to smoke then .
And I remember I had this cigarette when ‒
You know something strange ? John just suddenly got up ...
and rushed down to the pond ...
almost as if he knew something was going to ‒
- Well , it was too late . - Yes .
- It was strange . - Yes , of course .
- What ? - Of course .
He has the gift .
That 's why the child was trying to talk to him .
Even if he doesn 't know it .
Even if he 's resisting it .
It 's a curse as well as a gift .
[ Man Speaking Italian ]
[ John Shouts ]
It 's off center .
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Grunting ]
You can 't ...
ever contact people , can you ?
We 're often asked . She 's quite famous around Elgin .
They all want a lot of mumbo jumbo ...
about ectoplasm and holding hands .
Second sight is a gift from the good Lord , who sees all things ...
and I consider it an impertinence to call his creatures back from rest ...
for our entertainment .
It wouldn 't be for my entertainment .
Would you care to come back for tea when your husband 's finished ?
Just for a little while ?
Yes , I 'd like that . Thank you very much . Is that all right ?
I make no promises .
No .
- [ John ] It 's ridiculous ! - They only want to meet you .
I 'm not gonna get involved with two neurotic old women ...
in a session of mumbo jumbo ‒ no way !
I 've been trying very hard to hang on to myself ...
and to forget about what happened ...
to get rid of this emptiness .
It 's been with me like some pain . And finally ...
finally , through these two women , I 've discovered how .
They disapprove of mumbo jumbo too .
- They use that very word . - Of course they do .
- They just want to help , that 's all . - Laura , do you not see that what ‒
She 's gonna try and reach her .
Okay , Laura , that 's enough .
- Now , listen to me . - I 've listened to you .
You were the one who said , " Let the children play where they want to . "
You let her go near that pond .
Thanks for the memories , Laura . Thank you .
You said you 'd give your life in exchange for hers .
- Well , you can 't do that . - Jesus H. Christ !
John , she 's trying to get in touch with us .
- [ Children Chattering , Baby Crying ] - Maybe to forgive .
Okay , go on . Go on to your crazy women .
They can have their victim . Go on . Go on .
[ Man Singing In Italian On Radio ]
Here . Drink this . Whiskey .
Thank you . I don 't really need it , but thank you .
You may , child . You may .
I 'll be back in a jiffy .
Here you are .
[ Door Closes ]
Where are you ?
Me ? Oh , I 'm here .
Oh , the children .
- Who are you looking at ? - Um ‒
There 's a boy here with rolled-up shirtsleeves .
- Difficult to tell how old he is . - Yes , yes , yes . That 's Anthony .
And then there 's Charles next to him in his uniform .
- And then the three girls . - Mm-hmm . Yes .
And then there 's Angus .
- What ? This little bust ? - Yes .
Oh , that 's lovely .
Yes .
He ‒ He was a gentle child .
Oh . You haven 't touched your drink .
Uh , no .
Oh , is that Angus ?
I was just looking at the pictures of your family .
They 're wonderful .
It jars you , losing one like that . But I had two more .
So can you , I daresay .
Nothing can take the place of the one that 's gone .
Now , then .
- [ Cat Snarling ] - Oh , it 's all right .
It 's all right .
- [ People Chattering ] - [ Man Singing On Radio ]
[ Clock Chiming ]
Are your legs crossed ?
Yes .
- [ People Chattering ] - [ Man Singing On Radio ]
[ Clock Chiming ]
Switch the light out .
[ Cat Snarling ]
[ Horn Blaring ]
[ Moaning ]
Yes !
[ Panting ] Yes ! Yes !
Yes ! Yes !
Yes !
- Cosa fai ? - English .
John ! Yes !
- English . - [ Baby Crying ]
- Cosa fai qui ? - John ! Yes ! Yes !
- Ma chi sei ? - English .
[ Gasping , Moaning ]
- English . - Mario , che succede ?
- Yes ! Oh ! - Delinquente !
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Frenzied Moaning ]
What did she say ? What did she say ?
- What did she say ? - [ Wailing ]
What did she say ?
[ People Chattering ]
[ Italian Pop On Radio ]
I got scared for you .
I told you it was all right .
I was snooping .
Goddamn sisters .
- How much have you been drinking ? - [ Chuckles ]
You got scared for me , eh ? [ Chuckles ]
[ John Groans , Mutters ]
- You 're not going to be sick , are you ? - Screw them .
- You 're just not listening . - I am not going to be sick .
All right , John , now , listen : Heather , the blind one ...
she is really psychic .
She has second sight .
I mean , you 'd understand completely if you 'd ‒
Today when I was there , she ...
she went into the most incredible trance .
- Really , absolutely ‒ - Concentrate .
- Now , John ‒ - Yes ?
[ Sighs ] She said that ‒
that your life is in danger while you 're in Venice .
- She kept on and on saying it . - I am going to be sick .
[ Groaning ]
[ Toilet Flushes ]
I wouldn 't go in there for a couple of minutes if I were you .
I haven 't thrown up for ten years .
John ...
I really think we have to leave Venice .
- It was a warning . It was Christine . - Oh , Laura ‒
She was trying to warn us . How can I ‒
We must leave , John .
John , do you hear what I say ? It was Christine , our daughter !
My daughter is dead , Laura .
She does not come peeping with messages ...
back from behind the fucking grave !
Christine is dead ! She is dead !
Dead , dead , dead , dead , dead !
You must think I 'm ill , then .
Yeah .
If I 'm ill ...
I should be seeing Dr. Jameson .
Yep .
Maybe I am .
Maybe I left England too soon or something .
Maybe ‒ Maybe those women were influencing me .
Maybe I shouldn 't see them again . That 's what you want , isn 't it ?
Yep .
Maybe I should start taking my pills again .
They 're on the desk right there . There .
- [ Dog Barking ] - Here .
Here .
[ Woman Speaking , Faint ]
W-would ‒ You could ‒
You could get a couple of weeks or so off , couldn 't you ?
Yeah .
Could you ?
Yes .
Do you really think you could , John ?
- [ Clock Chiming ] - All right , Laura .
All right .
[ Door Closes ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Laura Moaning ]
[ Ringing ]
- Hello . - Hello .
- Pronto ? - [ Laura ] Who on earth is that ?
- Hello ? - Hello ?
[ Laura ] What 's the time , for God 's sake ?
Operator ?
- Operator ? - What 's the time ?
Operator ‒
Hello .
Operator , where is this call coming from ?
Uh , hello ?
- Hello ? - Where in England ?
- Oh , hello . Is that Mr. Baxter ? - John Baxter , yes .
Oh , good . Look , this is Anthony Babbage here .
- Yes ? - Headmaster at Porton School .
Yes . Yes , that 's right .
I 'm awfully sorry to get you so late at night , but , uh ‒
What time is it with you out there ?
Oh , I see . Look , we got your telephone number ...
from your London people , you see ?
Yes , well , the fact of the matter is there 's been a bit of an accident .
Mm-hmm . It 's your son , Johnny .
He 's been to the san and he 's in very capable hands ...
but Matron thinks , well , just poss ‒
Hello , Mr. Baxter ? It 's Mandy Babbage here .
Poor little Johnny . It was an accident during fire practice .
There 's nothing to worry about , but we did feel you ought to know .
Good . Yeah .
Mm-hmm .
Tell them I 'm catching the next plane home .
What ‒ What was that ?
My wife will be there this morning .
Yes . That 's very kind of you , Mrs. Babbage .
Thank you . Yes . Good night .
Good morning . Uh ‒
Bye .
This is what they meant about leaving Venice . They were right , you see ?
- This is it . This is what they meant . - [ Clicking Receiver ]
You see ?
Pronto ? Pronto ?
Will you get me Alitalia , please ?
Well , get me the airport , then .
What time do they open ?
Oh , Christ . Thank you . Yes , good night .
Darling , she said that she 's sure that he 'll be okay .
[ Italian ]
[ Italian Continues ]
A charter flight . We got the last seat .
Oh , fantastic !
He 's just finding out where they go from .
- Don 't forget to ask the bishop . - What ?
What we were talking about last night , about staying over in England .
- Oh , yeah . Three weeks ? - Whatever you can do .
' Cause I really feel I need time in England , away from Venice .
- I 'll tell him today . - You can 't come with me now ?
No .
You phone me tonight , and I 'll get away by the weekend .
[ Italian ]
Ten minutes .
The boat leaves in ten minutes from Riva degli Schiavoni .
Ten minutes , Mr. Baxter .
- Mr. Baxter ? - Sì ?
You are coming back ? We are closing .
Uh , I 'll collect ' em this morning .
[ Muttering In Italian ]
[ Gulls Calling ]
[ Italian ]
Give Johnny my love . Hold tight .
I 'll phone you tonight , okay ?
[ Men Speaking Italian ]
Beautifully done .
[ Italian ]
- Hello , John . - Good morning .
Morning .
I 'm sorry , but this church means a great deal to him .
You have all worked so hard , huh ?
- Are those the mosaics ? - Yes , they arrived this morning .
Is something the matter ?
Our son had an accident and , uh ...
Laura flew to London to see him at 4 : 00 this morning .
I will pray for you .
Oh , he 'll be okay .
Laura 's had some complications since ...
Christine , and ‒
You should have gone with her .
- Can I see the mosaics ? - Of course .
They 're marvelous .
The firm has worked for my family for over 200 years .
- Will they be able to match those ? - Oh , sure .
May I compare them ?
[ Laughing ]
Lower me down . Tirami giù .
Adagio , eh ?
[ Creaking ]
Sì , va bene .
[ Bells Tolling ]
[ Shouting In Italian ]
[ John Crying Out ]
[ Groans ]
[ Men Shouting In Italian ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Objects Clattering ]
[ Men Shouting In Italian ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Chuckling ]
- [ Gasping ] - [ Scattered Applause ]
[ Man Speaking Italian ]
- Tutto bene , architetto ? - Sì , sì , sì .
Would you like to sit down a few moments ?
No , I 'm gonna walk for a bit .
May I walk with you ?
Please .
My father was killed in a fall .
Yes ?
Yes .
It 's unbelievable .
What ?
My wife was warned ...
that I was in danger .
- " Warned " ? - [ Chuckles ]
It was , uh ‒
It was like , um ‒
It was a kind of prophesy .
I wish I didn 't have to believe in prophesy .
I do , but I wish I didn 't have to .
[ People Chattering ]
[ Children Shouting ]
Che è successo ?
Abbiamo trovato un corpo .
I hope it 's not another murder .
[ Children Laughing ]
- We should go . - [ Cries Out ]
[ Italian ]
[ Toilet Flushing ]
Mi scusi , sa , ma è già dopo mezzogiorno .
Pronto ?
The bishop 's driver will come by and pick up my things .
Thank you .
Laura !
[ Man ] Eh , vai piano !
Ah . Where is the manager ?
[ Italian ]
[ Man Whistling ]
[ People Whispering In Italian ]
Ah , signor Alexander . Has Mrs. ‒
Ah , signor Baxter . I-I thought you 'd ‒
The end of the season , you understand ?
- It 's my holiday . - [ Chuckles ]
Has Mrs. Baxter come back here ?
- The signora ? - My wife , yes . Has she come back here ?
Come back ? But she left this morning .
No , no , no . I just saw her on the Grand Canal .
Has she , uh ‒ Has she come back here ?
She missed the plane ?
No , I 'm just asking if my wife has come back here .
No , signore . We are closed .
We are closed .
[ Italian ]
[ Chuckling ]
- My luggage get away all right ? - Yes .
- You didn 't see my wife , did you ? - Uh , no .
Sì . Qui .
- Sì . - [ Man ] Signore , è pronto .
[ Italian ]
Hello .
Sit down , Mr. Baxter .
- This is your wife ? - Yes .
And these are the sketches .
How are they ?
Well , I guess you 'd recognize them from them .
Age makes women grow to look more like each other . Don 't you find that ?
Old men decay and each becomes quite distinct .
Women seem to converge , hmm ?
I hadn 't thought about it , but , uh ‒
The skill of the police artist ...
is to make the living appear dead .
Yeah .
You are no longer staying at the Europa ?
No . No , it closed for the winter this morning .
Now , tell me what happened , from the beginning .
My wife met these two women ...
a couple of days ago , and , uh ...
one of them , the blind one ...
claimed to have seen Christine , our dead daughter .
She said Christine was happy .
My wife collapsed ...
and when she came round , she was totally changed .
She was happy . She had come to terms with the death .
Uh , we ‒ She , uh ‒
She was her whole self again .
Did you have a row ?
A row ? No . Uh , well , yes .
Uh , I was only trying to protect her .
It was , uh ‒ But it was ‒
It didn 't make any difference because she went to see the women anyway ...
and then she came back , and , uh ‒
last night .
Then we went to bed . There was a call from England .
Our son goes to school in England , and the school phoned ...
to say that he had , uh ‒ had an accident .
My wife said that she had been warned ...
so I put her on the first plane to England this morning ...
and I saw her go .
I put her on the boat .
I saw her leave at 8 : 30 .
Have you called the airport ?
Yes . The plane was full . That 's all I know .
Please go on .
And then I saw her ...
between 10 : 30 and 11 : 00 on a boat .
I was on a vaporetto .
She 's here in Venice with those two women .
What is it , Mr. Baxter ?
I do not understand .
If she 's in Venice ...
surely she will get in touch with you .
If she can .
What is it you fear ?
Uh ‒
The killer on the loose , the murderer .
My wife is not a well woman .
Yes .
Yes , of course .
I hadn 't thought .
There must be more .
No , no , there 's nothing more .
My wife got something from these two women ‒
something that doctors couldn 't give her , that I couldn 't give her ...
something that she needed , so she went with them .
Where ‒ Where , I don 't know .
I was outside ‒
inside ‒ the pensione last night , where they lived .
And today before I came here , I went to look for it ...
and it 's ‒ it 's vanished .
So now she 's with them ?
Why should one criticize you for being worried ?
Thank you , Mr. Baxter , for talking to me .
I am grateful .
Okay , I 'll be at the Palazzo Vendori .
I want you to help me , Mr. Baxter .
Try again . Try and find the pensione .
It will make me feel ...
we have your cooperation in a real way .
[ Exhales Sharply ]
I , uh ‒
I don 't even know where to start . I-I ‒
Start from where ...
you saw them the last time .
- Okay . - Good luck .
- Thank you . - Where did you say ?
San Nicolò dei Mendicoli .
Ah , yes .
Pronto ? Sabbioni ?
Segua il signor Baxter dalla chiesa di San Nicola .
[ Piano Scales , Faint ]
[ Meows ]
[ Piano Scales Continue ]
[ Voice Calling ]
[ Men Shouting In Italian ]
- [ Shouting Continues ] - [ Beeping ]
[ Bird Twitters ]
Hello ? C 'è nessuno qui ?
Hello ?
Oh . Signora , buongiorno .
- Scusi . Parla inglese ? - No .
Due signore vecchie . Due sorelle . Una ‒
Mina ? Mina ?
Signora , buongiorno .
- Uh , due ‒ Parla inglese ? - No .
Due signore vecchie .
Sorelle .
Una ... come ‒
Come si dice ? Così .
- Ah ! - Sì ? Sì ?
- Venga , venga . - Scozie .
Sono uscite questa mattina presto .
- Una giovane signora è venuta a trovarle . - Sì ! Mia moglie !
[ Woman ] Venga , venga .
Ma dove sono ?
- Sono andate via . - Ma dove ?
Sono andate via questa mattina . Vuole la stanza ?
Io no . Grazie , no .
Dove ?
- Non lo so . Mina ? - Non lo so .
Scusi , signora . Thank you , Mr. Baxter .
- Chi è lei ? - Sabbioni .
Sezione omicidi . Murder squad .
- They 're not here . - [ Women Whispering ]
Yes . Very nice .
Very nice .
- Sì , signore ? - Il vescovo mi aspetta .
- Il suo nome , per favore . - Baxter . John Baxter .
Oh , Mr. Baxter . Yes , of course .
He 's got some people with him at the moment .
- I 'll just go tell him you 're here . - Thank you .
Eccellenza , c 'è il signor Baxter .
[ Footsteps Retreating ]
I referti medici sono pronti ?
Sì , Eccellenza .
- Oh , Sister ‒ - He won 't be long now .
I have to make a telephone call to England , which is urgent .
- Could I use that telephone ? - To England ?
You 'll just have to complete this form .
Thank you .
- Press this button ? - Yes .
[ Phone Dialing ]
[ John ] Pronto . Sì , per Inghilterra .
Mrs. Babbage ? John Baxter .
- Oh , hello , Mr. Baxter . - Hello .
I 'm so glad you called . We 've been trying to reach you ...
but the wires are down or some such silly nonsense .
Now , the main thing is Johnny 's absolutely fine .
- That 's terrific . - Quite right as rain .
He woke up this morning with no headache , no aftereffects ...
- Good . - and fit as a fiddle .
The doctor 's let him get up , and now he 's playing around .
He 's quite something of a hero at school .
The doctor doesn 't even think it 's concussion ...
because Johnny 's aware of the events that led up to it .
- That 's marvelous . - That 's something they have to watch out for , apparently .
- Yes . - I suppose you ‒
- I expect you 'd like to speak to your wife . - Sorry ?
- Here she is . - What ?
- I 've lost you . What ? - Hello , darling . What ?
- Laura ? - John , isn 't it ridiculous ?
It 's perfectly all right . Doctor James says there 's nothing wrong with him .
Absolutely nothing . He just has this little bump on his forehead .
- [ Laughing ] Laura , wh-where ‒ - Are you all right ? Where are you ?
- I 'm at Alberto 's . - Listen , darling .
I 'm catching the 9 : 00 plane over , so , um ‒
I don 't know what time it gets in , but we can have a late dinner .
- I thought I saw you in Venice . - And everything 's very good .
- Huh ? - John 's fine , and I 'm ‒
I 'm okay , okay ?
I thought I saw you here today .
I thought I saw you with the two sisters , with the two women .
I was certain . I swore it .
Darling , it 's all right . Don 't worry , sweetheart .
Listen , I 've just found the flight number .
- It 's , uh ‒ - Laura , where are you ?
I 'm at Porton , John .
Johnny and I just got back from having tea .
Now , my arrival time is 11 : 00 . It 's ‒
Just a second . I 've got a pencil .
- You stay at Alberto 's . I 'll come there . - Okay .
- Okay , I 'll wait ‒ - Stay there ...
and I 'll see you about 11 : 00 , all right ?
- Yeah . - Is that all right ?
- Okay . Yes . - Is that all right ?
Yeah . I love you . Bye .
- All right , darling . Bye . - Good-bye .
[ Italian ]
Amen .
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
John , are you feeling all right ?
Yeah , I 'm ‒ I 'm fine . Excuse me , Alberto .
Uh , I think . [ Chuckles ]
I just ‒ I have some things to ‒
- May I use your telephone ? - Sure .
[ Boys Chattering , Clapping ]
I really don 't blame you , moving in here .
- I would have done the same . - Yes , it 's very nice .
You do want to see Johnny again to say good-bye ?
[ Laura ] No , I 've already said good-bye .
Mrs. Baxter , I think it would be probably quicker ‒
Oh , yes , much .
Yes , I don 't want to miss that plane .
[ Continues , Indistinct ]
Le due sorelle inglesi ?
Sì , signore . Su per le scale , a destra , su di là .
Wendy ?
Answer me .
It 's me , John Baxter . Laura 's husband .
What 's happened to Wendy ? Where is she ?
I don 't know . I 'll find out . Are you all right ?
- I-I don 't know what 's happening . - Yes , I know .
[ Italian ]
Your sister has gone to the British consul .
Oh , yes , but that was hours ago .
It 's half past 9 : 00 now .
I don 't know this room . I want to go home , back to the hotel .
This is a police station . I don 't want to stay here , Mr. Baxter .
I-I can 't tell you how sorry I am .
It was a misunderstanding .
Yes , well , they took us out of our hotel .
We were arrested , and they asked us about your wife .
I know . I 'm-I 'm truly , truly sorry .
I 'm going to take you back to your hotel , all right ?
- Yes , please take me back . - Può andare ?
If I could just ...
- Oh , please . - take your arm .
You see , you can 't understand ...
the noises in a place like this .
I know . I 'm so sorry .
I just feel ‒
Well , yes , if you could just take me back .
[ Woman Speaking Over P.A. , Indistinct ]
- Signora Baxter ? - [ Italian ]
[ Italian ]
[ Heather ] One of the things I love about Venice ...
- is that it 's so safe for me to walk . - Steps .
- Thank you . - [ Liturgical Chanting , Faint ]
The sound changes , you see , as you come to a canal .
And the echoes from the walls are so clear .
My sister hates it .
That 's too bad .
She says it 's like a city in aspic ...
left over from a dinner party ...
and all the guests are dead and gone .
It frightens her .
Too many shadows .
We are almost there .
Yes .
Milton loved this city .
Did you know that ?
No . That 's interesting .
This isn 't the right way , is it ?
- The Palazzo di Conte Barbarigo ? - Sì , sì .
This is the wrong way .
I was told to take you to signor Baxter .
- Yeah ? - He is at the police station .
It is just on the way .
[ Foghorn Blows ]
- Puss , puss , puss , puss . - [ Cat Meows ]
- Puss , puss , puss . - [ Meows ]
I 've tried to keep them . They never stay .
Well , they 're very wild in Venice . They , uh ‒
- Do you like cats , Mr. Baxter ? - Oh , yeah .
Yes , I like them , all right . They don 't like me very much .
Yes , I like them .
- Here 's the hotel . - Thank you .
- These are swinging doors . - Yes , I remember .
I 'll keep them open .
So reassuring to have a man .
We changed hotels because Wendy said there were prowlers , and it was dirty .
- Careful of the steps . - Thank you .
Uh ... here 's the key , Mr. Baxter .
- Thank you . - Room 307 .
307 , yeah .
Okay , it 's here .
They said you 'd left when the consul took me back to the police station .
Oh , Wendy , you 're back . Mr. Baxter has been looking after me .
- Oh , has he ? - Well , uh ...
she was at the station and had been there for a while .
I thought that probably the best thing was to , uh ‒
- They found your wife , then ? - Yes . With the killings and ‒
He 's explained everything to me . Have we a drop of whiskey to offer Mr. Baxter ?
- You will stay a minute ? - Yes .
There 's the miniatures we got for Jessie .
We 're leaving tomorrow , Heather . The airplane 's been arranged .
- Have you put the photographs out ? - Here , on the dressing table .
None of that for me , thank you . Just a glass of water .
- I 'll fetch it . Do take a seat , Mr. Baxter . - Thank you .
So ...
you will be able to find it quite easily .
Thank you .
- Doesn 't really look like her . - It doesn 't matter .
- No ? - No .
Hmm .
Please . Your photograph .
What ?
My God .
Um , thank you very much .
And thanks for your help . Bye-bye .
Good-bye .
[ Paper Thuds , Rattles ]
Oh , thank you .
- You 're wearing odd socks . - You put out my clothes .
I know . I was merely informing you .
Thank you . Laura 's plane gets in . I 'd better be going .
- Let Mr. Baxter be off , Wendy . - Wait . Wait !
- Is there anything I can do ? - No , it 's all right .
- Good-bye . It 'll be all right . - Good-bye .
[ Crying Out ]
[ Wailing ]
[ Wailing Continues ]
- Wait . Wait ! - Fetch him back !
- Wait ! - Please ! Please !
Let him not go !
[ Heather Moaning ]
[ Anguished Moaning ]
Please , fetch him back !
Let him not go !
Please , let him not go !
Fetch him ! Fetch him !
Fetch him , woman ! Fetch him !
Fetch him back ! Fetch him back !
Oh , fetch him !
Mr. Baxter ? Mr. Baxter ?
- Mr. Baxter ! - [ Footsteps Running ]
Mr. Baxter !
[ Footsteps Continue ]
- Hello . Is John here ? - Quickly ! Come quickly !
- What is it ? - Quick ! Hurry !
What is it ?
Go on !
- [ Wendy ] Hurry ! Hurry ! - Is this it ?
- Please , Mrs. Baxter . - Is it Heather ?
Please .
- It 's Mrs. Baxter . - Where is he ?
I couldn 't find him .
Christine . I saw Christine .
- He left . - Find him .
- He just left . - Warn him .
You must find him . You must warn him .
- She told you . - When did he leave ?
- Where did he go ? - She told you .
- Where did he say he was going ? - She told you ...
- " Leave Venice . " - Oh , God !
She told him .
- Beware ! Beware ! - Wait !
[ Dog Barking ]
Laura ! Mrs. Baxter !
[ Switch Clicks ]
Hey ! Hey ! Hey !
Venga qui !
Qui , qui , qui . La barca . Qui .
No , no , no , la barca .
Espéreme , espéreme .
Espera .
Hey !
[ Man Shouting ] Brutto mostro !
Se ti acchiappo , ti ammazzo ! Maledetto !
[ John ] Dove vai ?
- Hey ! - Acchiappatelo ! Corri !
Bastarda !
Disgraziata !
Hey !
[ Groans ]
[ Footsteps Running ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
[ Metallic Creaking ]
[ Woman Speaking , Faint ]
[ Child Whimpering ]
Va bene .
Tutto va bene . Io amico .
I 'm coming .
[ Whimpering Continues ]
[ Shouting In Italian ]
It 's okay . It 's okay .
[ Crying ]
I 'm a friend .
I won 't hurt you .
Come on .
Darlings !
Wait . Wait .
- [ Screams ] - Wait .
- [ Screams ] - [ Bells Tolling ]
[ Bells Continue Tolling ]
[ Gulls Calling ]
Laura !
[ Bells Continue Tolling ]
[ Orchestral Flourish ]
[ Haunting ]
[ Ends ]